foreign
[Music]
again
ocdt brousseau 1187. all right well
another white game another E4 game
and let's see what our opponent throws
at us this time
well once again my official
recommendation is the alapin Sicilian
this is what we are focusing on in the
speedrun we're playing the elephant and
the Mora interchangeably
and we're facing D5 which as I've
indicated many times is one of Black's
two most reputable responses to the
elephant the other being Knight F6 which
is a smidge more popular these days
now D5 basically leads to a scandi with
the pawns on C3 and C5 which is clearly
in Black's favor because the pawn on C5
does the important job of controlling
the center whereas the pawn on C3 has
the unfortunate drawback of preventing
the knight from developing to its
rightful Square so if you want to think
of it as kind of a scandi with the move
C3 C5 included you can kind of do that
now of course the pawn on C3 also has a
benefit there is a reason we put it
there and the reason we put it there is
to prepare the move d4 occupying the
center with our pawn and at I would say
and I'm pulling this number a little bit
out of my butt but any number any like
rating Below in 18 1900 this is a a
tremendously dangerous position for
black it doesn't look that dangerous it
doesn't even look like white is imposing
any kind of
uh threats on black but if black
mishandles this position white gets a
massive initiative obviously the queen
on D5 is far from safe it can be chased
away in a variety of ways and one
mistake that people make right off the
bat here in many cases is that they take
on D4 prematurely and we've won a couple
of games that way
and of course the reason that taking on
D4 is often inaccurate is because it
opens up the C3 Square for White's night
allowing us to transition the game into
kind of normal scandi channels chasing
the queen away from D5 and when the
queen is chased away from D5 the pawn on
D4 can then frequently advance to D5
itself and if there's a knight on C6
white can in many cases develop a pretty
devastating initiative so I'm impressed
with our opponent's play Knight F6 is
the correct move and we of course
follow up with our own developing move
we play Knight F3 then we kind of play
this semi-weighting game hoping that
black takes on D4 and flinches first
as for our other pieces where we put
them depends entirely on the
developmental setup that black chooses
black has a lot of viable continuations
here
on a broad level the two main lines are
to play Bishop G4 this is the sort of
very ambitious developing move
and in response to Bishop G4 we have
Bishop B2 we also have this weird move
Knight beta D2 in order to set up Bishop
C4 we'll decide uh if our opponent plays
it and the second approach which has
been popular pretty recently I actually
just faced this in my Blitz session uh
right before the speed run is the
immediate E6 and this is what black
chooses in this game
now the benefit of E6 is that black
quickly accelerates uh his or her
kingside development Black's idea
broadly speaking is to play Bishop E7
and quickly tuck the king away on the
king side and you might say well what
about the C8 Bishop well the C8 Bishop
uh can be deployed oftentimes on the
long diagonal black and play B6 Bishop
B7 or black can just keep it on C8 for
the time being not every piece needs to
be Distributing the coveted vaccine now
if you watched carefully uh my actual
Blitz Games you will know what the move
is in this position
if you're not familiar with typical
alapin ideas this is a very hard move to
just figure out right if you were to
play based on general principles you
might come up with a move like Bishop E3
or maybe bishop D3 and Bishop D3 by the
way is one of the main lines
but the most meat on the bone can be
extracted not with a bishop move but
with a night move now you might say well
where are we gonna go with the knights
we go Knight bd2 not quite we actually
go Knight to A3 very very typical move
in the allopin and the idea is actually
threefold
the main point as you can probably guess
is to play a well-timed knight B5 that
threatens a family Fork on C7 and when
combined with the move Bishop F4 exerts
very serious pressure on Black's Queen
side so that's idea number one idea
number two is to use the Knight as an
anchor piece and prepare the aggressive
development of the light squared Bishop
to C4 which is also a Tempo move the
third idea comes in handy in the event
the black plays the move A6 which is one
of the main lines here A6 prevents
Knight B5 who could tell me what the
third idea is
the third idea is just a move that we
play in the event of A6
we don't play Bishop C4 there
we don't play Knight C2 Knight C2 is a
little bit passive we actually play
Knight C4
and why specifically in response to A6
well because you should notice that the
B6 square is a massive weakness in that
case and Knight C4 threatens another
Fork on B6
and it's not so easy for black to to
defend the square on B6 while keeping
his pieces active because the last thing
black wants to do is just drop the queen
back to d8 that's passive and that often
gives way an advantage and yet that's
often precisely what black has to do in
order to protect these key squares C
takes D4
now here
we refrain from the move a lot of people
are tempted by which is Bishop C4
tempting move but it's wrong because the
queen has this very nasty check on e4 so
Bishop C4 is wrong
instead we make a different Intermezzo
we play Knight B5 we play Knight B5 now
this is the main idea of the previous
move
and you might say well wait a minute
what about Queen E4 check here well
Queen E4 check doesn't actually solve
the problem of Knight C7 after Queenie
forech we play Bishop B2 and even though
Knight C7 doesn't Fork the king and the
queen anymore it still Forks the king in
The Rook so it's still a massive threat
and black has no choice but to protect
the C7 Square there are several ways to
do that the main move in this position
is to drop the queen all the way back to
d8
black can also do it with the bishop and
that's exactly what our opponent just
did Bishop to D6 but this is already a
serious inaccuracy in this hands white
uh a pretty sizable positional Advantage
it's not a terrible move Bishop D6 is
actually okay
but it gives us a major advantage and an
initiative so there's a couple of things
that white can do the Soviet Schoolboy
method would be to say okay well we can
just play Knight takes D6 check and we
can collect the bishop pair and then we
can recapture the pawn on D4 and it
should make sense to everybody that in
the resulting position white is
positionally better we have the bishop
pair
uh we have an open in with an open
Center our Bishops are nicely placed we
can bring one Bishop to D3 and the other
Bishop maybe to G5 and black still has
to deal with the issue that his
remaining Bishop is stuck behind the
pawn chain so Knight takes D6 check
nothing rod with it but in the spirit of
the elephant we can try to extract as
much juice out of this position as
possible especially given that we know
the queen is a very bad Defender when
the queen defends a minor piece that
construction is always going to be prone
to a lot of different tactics so what
move can we try on the basis of that
well a lot of you are coming up with the
idea of pushing C4 the problem with C4
is that it's a very leaky move C4 opens
up the diagonal and allows Bishop B4
check intermezzo
Zen black trades the bishop on B4 and
drops the queen back to d8 it's not the
end of the world for white but it's not
effective also after C4 black can drop
the queen into C5 kind of a weird square
but I don't see a good way to attack the
queen when it lands on C5
so instead of pushing C4 we can do the
same thing the same exact thing but
while we're at it we can continue our
development and make a more serious
threat against Black's Queen the move is
Bishop to C4
I might say well I don't get how that
differs substantively from the move C4
well first of all it's a developing move
and that in and of itself is already
good
but where you see the real benefit of
playing Bishop C4 over the move C4
is that if black plays now the move
Queen to C5 we have kept open the
possibility of then playing C takes D4
and everybody should see by the way why
the bishop cannot be captured the reason
is that we recapture on D6 and that is
once again a fork on the queen and the
King
now black still has the move Queen E4
check and that might seem scary to you
but Queen e4check is a total paper tiger
we can block that check with our Bishop
we can even move the king away and
Black's lack of development is going to
cost him very dearly because the bishop
on D6 has to remain on that diagonal in
order to prevent Knight C7 checks so in
the resulting position black has to
tread very carefully in order to avoid
losing more material so King F1 here is
possible but I want to play this a
little bit less adventurously I think
that we should just play a simple move
actually we can play Bishop to E3 talk
about sexy Bishop E3 might even be the
best move in the position
I was gonna propose Bishop E2
but Bishop E3 is a well-known idea in
these types of lines believe it or not
I've seen a line where Bishop E3 is the
main theoretical move I will show you
after the game
and Bishop E3 looks fantastic because
guess what we're just completing our
development
we're just making developing moves and
this is not as outlandish as it might
seem if you understand the mechanism of
how this move works
right the fact that the D6 Bishop is
hanging with a fork is so important
black has to spend a Tempo defending the
bishop or moving it and after that we
will finally recapture the pawn on D4
and we will have a massive lead in
development a monster Knight on B5 and
the Queen on e4 is now more vulnerable
than ever because when you've got a
queen that's out in the center like this
and none of the other pieces are
developed the queen is liable to get
trapped or get attacked and black is
already in serious trouble it took us
nine moves
King E7 whoa that is a surprise
and again we have to switch gears
seamlessly
right stage one was the fun part right
we brought all our pieces out we were
using tactics stage two is a little bit
less glamorous this is where we actually
reap the rewards of our fine opening
play
but we actually just play it very simple
here so first question we should resolve
is whether or not we should take the
bishop on D6 should we snap this bishop
off the board or or do we take on D4
straight away
well the answer I think can largely be
yielded intuitively Knight takes D6
doesn't really have a downside we get
the bishop pair
and especially in the context of Black's
previous move don't you want to drive
the king out to D6
and then in the resulting position we
definitely want to snap the bishop off
in the resulting position we don't want
to trade Queens here
is white better in that end game
absolutely white is still better in that
end game but we want to go for checkmate
with no development on the King sitting
on D6 what do we actually recapture on
D4 with
well we can't take with the bishop
because the bishop is pinned
taking with the Pawn closes down the D
file and the D file is going to be the
main attacking Avenue we of course want
to take on D4 with the Knight
and it should be very clear to you that
in that position after King takes D6
Knight takes D4 Queen takes G2 is as
non-threatening as a move can possibly
get because we can go Knight F5 check
and we're gonna have Checkmate Seven
Ways to Sunday there
I mean we don't even have to calculate
it I'm not calculating that line we'll
cross that bridge if we get there but
there is no way that black can get away
with Queen takes G2 in that position
and looking more specifically as we take
on D4 with the Knight after Queen takes
G2 I think Knight F5 double check leads
to forced mate
double check followed by a check on D6
and we hunt the king down pretty
straightforward now what's funny is that
after Queen takes G2
if you didn't see Knight F5 check
the crazy thing is even a move like Rook
F1 preserves a devastating attack
against Black's King so it's just a pawn
it's just a pun but I hope black takes
it so we can have fun King E7 good play
by our opponent King E7 I think is the
only way for black to stay alive they
have to move the king away from the
potential discover check now again this
is the part of the game where a lot of
players struggle because you're kind of
rearing to go you're looking for The
Knockout but there is no knockout we
don't have enough pieces in the attack
now I would briefly check if I were
white uh a move like Knight F5 check
maybe try to go Bishop C5 but none of
that works because the bishop is also
pinned and that's the key Insight the
bishop is pinned we need to unpin
ourselves and the way that we do that is
by simply Castle in kingside
now this accomplishes several things as
I said it unpins the bishop but it also
prepares to deploy The Rook our next
move is very likely to be Rook to E1 in
order to harass the queen and try to
force the queen out of E4
and by forcing the queen out of E4 we're
also opening up the e-file and setting
up possibilities of Knight F5 check Etc
Rook to Da still good defensive player
by our opponent well we continue
deploying our pieces with Rook to E1
of course we are totally not afraid of
the move E5 here there is no way that E5
is going to work out for black given his
total lack of development
in fact I think after E5 the clinical
move is Bishop E3 to G5 and this might
actually happen that forces the queen
away and the queen has nowhere to go
such that it maintains contact with the
E5 Pawn black is going to lose that pawn
on E5 with a check now do we have a
threat here well E5 is played so once
again why did our opponent play E5 well
our opponent sees the fact that the
Knight can't move and he gets excited
something that you should notice is that
black does not even have a threat we
could literally play A4 here and we
would still probably be winning
why is that because if black plays e
takes D4 we just recapture with the
bishop and the Queen on e4 is pinned
anytime you have alignment between the
king and the queen that is an incredibly
vulnerable tactical situation but that
doesn't mean we're gonna play A4 we are
going to move the bishop away onto the
best possible Square what is the best
possible Square for the bishop well it's
not F4 I can see some people falling for
Bishop F4 that simply blunders the
bishop on F4 of course the best square
is G5 because it also pins the Knight
and it most importantly forces the queen
away what squares do the queen have it
have at its disposal not many F5 is
covered F4 is covered so those are the
two squares where the queen keeps
contact with the E5 Pawn
Queen G6 or queen G4 is forced and then
of course we grab the pawn on E5 we
force the king back to f8 and who sees
the crushing move in that resulting
position again a direct consequence of
the fact that black has not developed
any part of their Queen side
yeah G6 sorry if I said G5
what's the move after Queen G6 Rook
takes C5 king f8 of course the move is
Knight T4 to E6 an elementary Discovery
Against The Rook on d8 and that leads to
force checkmate
simple straightforward attacking chess
but what really made the wheels of the
attack turn
first of all is the fact that we took on
D6 at the right moment so we forced
black to waste a bunch of Tempe moving
back and forth but castles and rookie
one these are the two moves that you
should really pay attention to and you
should make sure that you would play
these types of Moves In your own game
that you wouldn't get tempted by some
speculative attacking approach
the role of patients in attacking cannot
be overstated and this is a good lesson
a good introductory lesson in that
regard
this is GG
now black can try Rook takes D4
but then we just recapture with a pawn
preserving all of our threats
and then even D takes E5 is crushing
yeah simple game 14 moves you can see
that we are not compromising on the
danger level
just because we're playing an elephant
rather than Amora I promised you that
and I think you can see that in effect
if I was watching this on YouTube I
would Ponder the idea that these were
paid actors your ideas always work out
well for now right and one thing that
you can observe and I think this is one
of the reasons people like the speed run
is slowly but surely the games start to
become a little bit less smooth right
now it just seems like I play the moves
in the opening and then they work
perfectly and we're winning by move 15
every single time and we are when we hit
16 1700 even a little bit earlier than
that
you can start to see that my ideas don't
always work out perfectly I make some
inaccuracies the games last a lot longer
on average
but that's I think part of what makes it
fun okay Queen takes E1 well that gives
up the queen that actually might be the
best that black can do
crazily enough that's how lost he is
but obviously
it goes without saying that the Knight
on D4 is Untouchable because the E5 Pawn
is pinned and our attack simply
continues just because we're up a queen
doesn't mean that we are pausing our
attack
black cannot even get a rook and a piece
for the queen what's going on here well
we have a queen for a rook which is a
totally overwhelming material advantage
but more importantly we have a raging
attack on the black king
if the Knight
comes out to D7 if the Knight comes out
to D7 how are we going to actually win
the pawn on E5 there's a very nice move
and a very instructive move against
Knight b87 which has been played who can
spot this move
an important concept to keep in mind
right using your pawns to just blast
through the gates here the best move
is just to play F4 very nice F4 is
crushing notice how we're using the
queen as the pinning piece and we're
using the pawn as the main attacker and
we're using the pin against the Knight
on E7 sorry the Knight on F6
to ensure that after E4 we can just pick
up the pawn on e4 now what should we do
here
in order to figure that out you should
understand that the ultimate goal for
white the fastest way to win a game like
this is just to open up as many files as
possible it's not really to win pawns we
already have an extra Queen so what's
the best way to just blast open the
e-file the f file as many files as you
can it's not Bishop takes F6 it's just F
takes E5 this is the simplest way and
this should make sense to because after
hgeef we've opened up both the E and the
f file and the King has no Safe Haven if
it moves to the f-file we follow it to
the f file with our Queen
if it moves back to f8 then Queen E7
check leads to Checkmate if King D6 then
still Queen E7 everywhere the King goes
we just tail it with our Queen and this
is made in three moves we don't even
take the Rook on d8 we take on F7 and
take on G7 with Checkmate bang and then
bang and that's the best way to finish
the game
so again a simple game but if you're
watching and you're finding this to be
boring try to focus on kind of building
fundamentals and making sure that your
fundamentals are in place that you would
play the same moves that I played in
this game
so a little bit of opening Theory here a
little bit of opening Theory
D5 is impressive from from someone at
his level a lot of people know the
basics which is great
so after D4 Knight F6 Knight F3 leads to
an incredibly uh famous and well-studied
theoretical position E6 is a good move
um and I had this recently against our
generic icy in AIM chess I also had this
in a classical game in the US Open
against the GM where where I won a nice
game we actually had this exact position
now if I remember correctly Black's two
best moves in this position are
considered to be first of all A6 which I
mentioned during the game
and here the line goes Knight C4
how is black going to defend B6 who can
tell me the best way for black to defend
the B6 Square can black do it while
developing a piece
yeah Knight B8 to D7 this is an
important move
and Black's next move is very likely to
be B7 B5 chase the Knight away from C4
and prepare the deployment of the light
squared Bishop to B7
now you might wonder let's say you're a
you know you're a GM
and
you know where do you go from here let's
say you want to study this position well
that's where opening books are so
valuable you would just pull out the
Elephant book which I know all of you
guys have and you would check what the
authors recommend in this position
that's really all you do in many cases
to deepen your knowledge of of important
theoretical positions and that's what I
can do right now
to lock the book
and orienting yourself in these long
opening books can be difficult but the
table of contents usually has
a pretty good overview of all of the
pertinent lines
okay 242. there we go
yep I see it now
so what the authors recommend in
squeezing the Sicilian
squeezing the Sicilian is
yeah Knight A3 G3 A6 yeah page 292
Knight C4 nbd7 they just give Bishop E2
and they say here it deserves attention
for white to try A4 restricting Black's
possibilities on the queen side so
interesting
uh alternative but their main line is
Bishop E2
and now they give a bunch of analysis
but their main line is C takes D4 Knight
takes D4
now Queen takes G2 allows Bishop F3 with
a massive Initiative for white
and they give a bunch of analysis here
with the upshot that white has huge
compensation for the pawn
and the main line here is E5 trying to
force the queen trade now we sync the
sync our teeth into F5
and they say that in the events of the
queen trade white is a slight Advantage
According to some correspondence game
fill on against Salon from 2008 Knight
ft6 check yeah clearly white is slightly
better here
and if black tries to trade on his own
terms with Knight C5
then according to the authors you drop
the Knight back to E3
you force the queen trade and they claim
the white is slightly better in this
position due to
the improved placement of the Knight on
C4
so this is really what opening study
starts to look like when you cross like
a certain level I wouldn't recommend a
600 to purchase a book like this and
spend hours digging around in opening
Theory but that's really all there is to
it when you want to deepen your
knowledge of critical theoretical lines
so Asics might not fully equalize
our opponent plays C takes D4 which is
of course in the engine does support
that this is a pretty recent book there
definitely are holes in that book it's
it's was written in 2020 so already the
engines have gotten stronger but you can
still very much rely on resources I
would say from 2015 onwards if you're
anybody except Magnus Carlson any book
written past 2015 on the opening
by a solid player by a GM you can not
necessarily trust verbatim but you can
use as as a base
so C takes D4 we play Knight B5
threatening Knight C7 and here of course
came a massive Mistake by black
conceptually the move Bishop D6 makes
sense black tries to defend the square
on C7 while developing a piece but doing
so with the bishop is just a very
inefficient use of resources due to this
very nasty response Bishop C4
so what was the correct move in this
position the only correct move is Knight
to A6 very typical move and Knight A6 is
ubiquitous across many different
openings where a knight lands on B5
and what comes to mind as as a
comparison is the jababa London which is
a totally unrelated opening but an
opening that also features in many cases
the move Knight B5 as early as move four
and here you often see black going
Knight A6 which is a nice Square from
which to defend the C7 Pawn
so
um so so Knight A6 is a move no I I
mentioned Queen D7 but that's in a
different position uh Queen D7 is the
move if black plays in this position
Knight C6
and white plays Knight B5 which I
actually just had in a Blitz game here
Queen D7 I think is the topical move
that's supposed to equalize but don't
quote me on that you can do your own
research here
so CD4 Knight B5 Knight A6 is the main
move
and here white normally plays Queen
takes D4 although you can also play
Knight B takes D4 and I think in all
cases white is better I think white is
solidly better in this position this I
think is what the authors recommend
and if memory serves me right they give
this line Bishop E7 Bishop E5 check
Bishop D7 and now something to keep the
tension like Queen E2 and black is just
a little bit cramped and the Queen on D5
in such positions uh is obviously very
vulnerable like if black castles and
White Castles Rook D1 is coming to a
theater near you and that's going to
cause massive anguish to black screen
why is slightly better it's it's it's
more comfortable to play this with white
so hopefully this opening overview isn't
too boring in any case Bishop D6 Bishop
C4 leads to massively unpleasant
consequences for black
um well King d8 King d8 is a huge
concession right if you have to go King
d8 to protect the C7 Square I'm just
going to take on D4 and say hey your
King's terrible and I'm just going to
continue developing
right so Bishop D6 Bishop C4 Queen E4
check and Bishop E3 is a sexy move and I
wanted to show you another line where
Bishop E3 is the main theoretical move
yeah the engine likes Queen takes D4
which is a totally legitimate move
because after Queen takes D4 Knight f64
I'll tell you what I what I missed
I thought that after Bishop E5 black is
stable but here there is an incredibly
strong move who can find this move
there's a hidden move here that wins
material for white and it's not F4 I
know some of you are probably thinking
F4 I can guarantee it it's not F4
and the reason it's not F4 is because of
Bishop takes D4 and something that you
should note down don't stop calculating
just because you win The Rook on A8 you
have to make sure that a situation
doesn't arise where black has already
won one minor piece and is likely to win
a second one with B6 Bishop B7 so
this is a very double-edged position but
you can avoid all of this
by doing the same thing in a different
way Knight D4 to F3 is incredibly strong
exactly it prevents Bishop takes D4 and
black has no choice black has no choice
but to play A6 losing a healthy Pawn in
the end game white should be technically
winning here
so that was the engine's Preferred
Choice I didn't see Knight F3 from a
distance but I still like Bishop C4
and the final opening note that I'll
make the line in which Bishop E3 is
featured if memory serves me right is
this line where black plays G6 which is
a viable sub-variation of the D5 line
and after Knight F3 Bishop G7 white
again goes Knight A3 and there's an old
line where white plays C takes D4
now white plays Bishop C4 that's a move
that we did not play uh in in the game
but the position is different and after
Queen E4 check if you've never seen this
move before it's an absolutely stunning
idea what is White's move White's move
is Bishop to E3 this is actual Theory
and who can figure out the idea after d
take C3 what the heck is white doing
here well like I said anytime there's a
queen and it's in the center and you're
not very well developed there's going to
be tactics
but not Bishop B5 check I know some of
you are thinking I see Checkmate but the
check on B5 can be easily parried with
Knight C6
no no no the move is Bishop takes F7
check stock tactic
and if King F7 you get forked on G5 and
actually most importantly if King f8 you
have the additional check on d8 without
this check the whole line would fall
apart forcing King takes F7 and Knight
G5 truck wins the queen with checkmate
so it's a beautiful move Bishop B3 and
because of the threat of Bishop takes F7
black is forced to spend a Tempo getting
the Knight out to H6 and now white just
recaptures on T4 and according to Modern
Theory white is better due to uh his
lead in development and just due to the
activity of White's pieces so just a
cool thing to file into your mental kind
of Rolodex Bishop B3 is a known idea in
a different position ironically enough
we of course played it in a much simpler
instantiation here we don't have to
calculate anything because Knight takes
D6 just wins the game
um but King E7 is the decisive mistake
no question about it after Knight takes
D4 we are already or sorry Bishop D6
with the decisive mistake here we're
already completely winning there's just
no way the black can truly defend this
given the pathetic King situation
now if Magnus Carlson were sitting with
the black pieces then after Rook d8
rookie one he would probably play the
move Queen G6 and the game does continue
here
a lot of you pointed out Knight F5 check
this still does not work it doesn't work
because if Queen takes F5 and even if
you could play Bishop C5 it would still
not work because of King E8
so again in such a position it's so
important to be patient who can give me
an example of a nice solid patient
improving move for white there's a
couple of moves like that but let's see
if you can generate a couple of good
Alternatives here with white yeah love
the move Queen B3 aiming the queen at B7
and aiming at a D6 similarly I love the
move Queen to F3 get the queen onto a
nice square and then bring the Rook to
D1 play it's simple now Queen F3 might
be inaccurate because of Queen G4 and
this forces a queen trade which
obviously is in Black's favor
the engine actually proposes a more
brute force method it proposes the move
Bishop back to D3 in order to eliminate
the pin against the queen and open up
the possibility now finally of that
check on F5 which all of you wanted to
deliver Queen H5 Knight F5 check is
clearly already possible because now
after he takes F5 you have Checkmate
starting with Bishop C5
oh and look at this mate rookie7
Queen A4 sack another minor piece check
here check here and mate on C4
amazing line and just look at the sorry
state of Black's pieces this is all you
need to know
so lots of Juicy spicy lines like this
now black has a creative defensive idea
here Queen takes F5
Bishop takes F5 Rook a takes D1 Rook
takes D1 but what's amazing is that
black loses here because EF5 Bishop C5
is literally double check and mate look
at how White's pieces are all in perfect
Symphony here coordinated and depriving
the king of all squares
so incredible lines here and after
Knight F5 if black plays King f8 then oh
my God look at the engine move here this
is amazing
Bishop D3 to E2
holy and I'm just gonna throw in the
customer holy s word
because the Rook is hanging on d8 right
so black has to take the queen
now a critical move for white you have
to throw in the Intermezzo Bishop C5
check
this forces the king to move to G8 and
hopefully by now you see the idea if
Black Goes King Ian instead then you
would go Knight takes G7 and you win
everything
but after King G8 you simply play Rook a
takes D1 with a double attack you're
threatening Checkmate and you're
threatening to win the queen back and
black cannot get all of the material
back for the queen Black's gonna be down
in exchange
incredible now why do you need Bishop C5
because if you were to take immediately
then black wins after Queen takes F5
you can't play Bishop C5 anymore and
Rook d8 is now futile on account of King
E7 so at some point these games become
tactical and when they do you have to
calculate accurately you have to be
ready to find Creative Solutions
but hopefully you know this this
inspires you a little bit these lines
aren't necessarily all that instructive
but they just illustrate the potential
that you have when you patiently deploy
all of your pieces so Bishop D3 is the
best move in the Knight of five to
follow but the human move is something
like Queen B3 or queen F3 even a slow
move like H3 nothing wrong with this
this keeps a huge Advantage as well
so in any case E5 Bishop G5 of course
ends the game immediately just to
reiterate after Queen G6 Rook takes C5
Chuck king f8 and the easiest winning
move is Knight to E6 check picking up
the Rook on d8 you simply cannot survive
if you're playing Black without
developing any of your pieces which is
why if I'm playing Black here I would go
either Queen G6 or maybe even Knight C6
desperately trying to bring your pieces
into the game
anyways E5 Bishop G5 our opponent gave
up the queen and F4 not taking our foot
off the gas pedal knocking off the E5
Pawn opening up as many files as
possible and checkmating with Queen F7
Queen G7
pretty simple game
but I think it led to a nice discussion
of opening Theory I'm starting to kind
of introduce to you the general tenets
of the elephant Sicilian if you know you
have a hankering for more elephant
content you can find plenty of it
already on my YouTube channel I've had
so many Speed Run games in the alapin
and you could just search by opening
but we will have many more allopins and
we will have a lot more discussion of
opening theory for now I think it's a
good time for us to end I'm gonna
probably put both of these games in the
same video it's gonna be a long one
um or I might separate it I'll ask my
editor what he thinks but I hope you
guys enjoyed the two Speed Run games
today I think they were fun we're still
in the
area where the games are basically
straightforward and most of them are
decided in the opening and that's going
to be the case for another 100 150
points but that's okay that allows us to
build a solid foundation and talk about
Theory and uh I hope I hope you're
enjoying the games even if they're
one-sided thank you everybody for
hanging out and again if you aren't
subscribed to my YouTube and you want to
support my content in an easy way the
best thing to do is to subscribe to the
YouTube keep growing the channel thank
you everybody have a good one and
hopefully see you tomorrow for more SEC
action rating Hannah thanks for hanging
out and I'll see you guys later
[Music]